Thomas Adriance Papers, 1957, 1971-1995
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Thomas Adriance Papers, 1957, 1971-1995
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1996-003
3 boxes; 4.2 cu. ft.
The collection consists almost exclusively of performance programs, playbills, and other threater literature of theater, dance, and music performances attended by Adriance.
Thomas Adriance
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Thomas Adriance Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1996.
Biographical Information
Thomas Adriance was born in 1937 and educated at Dartmouth College (B.A., 1959) and Columbia University (Ph.D., 1968). He served as an Assistant and then Associate Professor of History at Virginia Tech from 1968 until his death in February 1996, specializing in French History and military battles.
Scope and Content
The collection consists almost exclusively of performance programs, playbills, and other threater literature of theater, dance, and music performances attended by Adriance. The performances were given in Blacksburg, Virginia, and other regional, national, and international locations. Includes programs from performances at the Barter Theatre in Abingdon, Virginia, the Kennedy Center in Washington, D.C., and the Opera de Paris in France.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by event location.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Faculty; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Virginia Tech, Audobon Quartet performances, 1980-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Virginia Tech, Dance performances, 1980-1986, 1987, 1989, 1991, 1993. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Virginia Tech, Dance performances. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Virginia Tech, Music performances, 1978, 1980-1983. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Virginia Tech, Music performances, 1983-1986, 1991-1992. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Virginia Tech, Music performances. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Virginia Tech, Theater/Opera performances, 1979-1984. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Virginia Tech, Theater/Opera performances, 1984-1991. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Virginia Tech, Theater/Opera performances, 1992-1995. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Virginia Tech, Theater/Opera performances. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Blacksburg, Virginia, Blacksburg High School Auditorium. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Blacksburg, Virginia, Christ Episcopal Church, 1979, 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Blacksburg, Virginia, Playmakers Playhouse at University Mall, 1993-1994. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Abingdon, Virginia, Barter Theater, 1979-1983. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Abingdon, Virginia, Barter Theater, 1983, 1985-1986. (Box-folder 1:15)
- Abingdon, Virginia, Barter Theater, 1987-1988, 1991-1993. (Box-folder 1:16)
- Abingdon, Virginia, Barter Theater, 1994-1996. (Box-folder 1:17)
- Radford, Virginia, Radford University-Porterfield Theater, 1985, 1989, 1992. (Box-folder 1:18)
- Radford, Virginia, Radford University-Preston Auditorium, 1979-1987, 1989, 1992-1994. (Box-folder 1:19)
- Radford, Virginia, Radford University, 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 1:20)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Mill Mountain Theater, 1979-1980, 1983-1985. (Box-folder 1:21)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Mill Mountain Theater, 1986-1988. (Box-folder 1:22)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Mill Mountain Theater, 1988-1989, 1991-1992. (Box-folder 1:23)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Mill Mountain Theater, 1992-1995. (Box-folder 1:24)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Opera Roanoke, 1991-1995. (Box-folder 1:25)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Roanoke Ballet, 1981-1982. (Box-folder 1:26)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Roanoke Civic Center, 1980-1981, 1983, 1988, 1993. (Box-folder 1:27)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Roanoke College-Olin Theater, 1981-1985, 1988. (Box-folder 1:28)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Roanoke Symphony Orchestra, 1980-1985. (Box-folder 1:29)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Roanoke Symphony Orchestra, 1985-1989. (Box-folder 1:30)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Roanoke Symphony Orchestra, 1989-1995. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Roanoke, Virginia, Southwest Virginia Opera Society, 1980-1984, 1986-1991. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Bluefield, West Virginia, Bluefield College, 1984. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Washington, D.C., Arena Stage, 1978, 1980-1983. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Washington, D.C., Arena Stage, 1984-1985, 1991-1994. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Washington, D.C., Back Alley Productions. (Box-folder 2:6)
- Washington, D.C., Church Street Theater, 1983. (Box-folder 2:7)
- Washington, D.C., Columbia Station Cabaret Theater. (Box-folder 2:8)
- Washington, D.C., Folger Theater, 1980-1984, 1988-1989. (Box-folder 2:9)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1975-1977. (Box-folder 2:10)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1978-1979. (Box-folder 2:11)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1980-1981. (Box-folder 2:12)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1982. (Box-folder 2:13)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1983. (Box-folder 2:14)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1984. (Box-folder 2:15)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1985-1986. (Box-folder 2:16)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1987-1988. (Box-folder 2:17)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1989-1991. (Box-folder 2:18)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1992-1993. (Box-folder 2:19)
- Washington, D.C., Kennedy Center, 1994-1995. (Box-folder 2:20)
- Washington, D.C., Lisner Auditorium, 1987. (Box-folder 2:21)
- Washington, D.C., National Gallery of Art, 1983. (Box-folder 2:22)
- Washington, D.C., National Theater, 1979, 1981, 1984. (Box-folder 2:23)
- Washington, D.C., Phillips Collection, 1983. (Box-folder 2:24)
- Washington, D.C., Studio Theater, 1984, 1992. (Box-folder 2:25)
- Washington, D.C., Warner Theater, 1986-1987. (Box-folder 2:26)
- Washington, D.C., Washington Cathedral, 1980. (Box-folder 2:27)
- Washington, D.C., Woolly Mammoth Theater Company, 1994. (Box-folder 2:28)
- Clearwater, Florida, Showboat Dinner Theater, 1990. (Box-folder 2:29)
- Key West, Florida, Red Barn Theater, 1988-1991. (Box-folder 2:30)
- Sarasota, Florida, Asolo Theater, 1980, 1983. (Box-folder 2:31)
- Cambridge, New York, L'Ensemble, 1983. (Box-folder 2:32)
- Lake George, New York, Lake George Opera Festival, 1976, 1978-1980. (Box-folder 2:33)
- Lake George, New York, Lake George Opera Festival, 1981-1984. (Box-folder 3:1)
- Lake George, New York, Lake George Opera Festival, 1985, 1987-1988, 1990. (Box-folder 3:2)
- Katonah, New York, Caramoor Festival, 1981. (Box-folder 3:3)
- New York, New York, Ambassador Theater, 1982. (Box-folder 3:4)
- New York, New York, Booth Theater, 1981. (Box-folder 3:5)
- New York, New York, Carnegie Hall, 1983. (Box-folder 3:6)
- New York, New York, Circle in the Square Theater, 1983. (Box-folder 3:7)
- New York, New York, City Center, 1982. (Box-folder 3:8)
- New York, New York, City Center, 1985. (Box-folder 3:9)
- New York, New York, Eastside Playhouse, 1983. (Box-folder 3:10)
- New York, New York, Gay American Arts Festival. (Box-folder 3:11)
- New York, New York, Lincoln Center, 1971-1972, 1978-1979, 1981, 1983, 1985. (Box-folder 3:12)
- New York, New York, Lucille Lortel Theater, 1982. (Box-folder 3:13)
- New York, New York, Meridian Gay Theater, 1983. (Box-folder 3:14)
- New York, New York, New Apollo Theater, 1979. (Box-folder 3:15)
- New York, New York, New World Theater, 1981-1982. (Box-folder 3:16)
- New York, New York, New York City Opera, 1979, 1982. (Box-folder 3:17)
- New York, New York, Palace Theater, 1985. (Box-folder 3:18)
- New York, New York, Roundabout Theater Company. 1985. (Box-folder 3:19)
- New York, New York, Westside Arts Theater, 1983. (Box-folder 3:20)
- Salem, New York, Fort Salem Theater, 1983. (Box-folder 3:21)
- Saratoga, New York, Saratoga Performing Arts Center, 1976, 1978-1981. (Box-folder 3:22)
- Saratoga, New York, Saratoga Performing Arts Center, 1982-1984. (Box-folder 3:23)
- Saratoga, New York, Saratoga Performing Arts Center, 1985, 1987, 1990. (Box-folder 3:24)
- Saratoga, New York, Saratoga Performing Arts Center. (Box-folder 3:25)
- Charlotte, North Carolina, Charlotte Opera, 1980-1983. (Box-folder 3:26)
- Charlotte, North Carolina, Charlotte Opera, 1984-1986. (Box-folder 3:27)
- Charlotte, North Carolina, Opera Carolina, 1986-1987. (Box-folder 3:28)
- High Point, North Carolina, North Carolina Shakespeare Festival, 1979, 1994. (Box-folder 3:29)
- Winston Salem, North Carolina, Reynolds Auditorium 1981. (Box-folder 3:30)
- Gettysburg, Pennsylvania, CPC Summer Theater, 1981. (Box-folder 3:31)
- Columbia, South Carolina, University of South Carolina at Columbia, 1988. (Box-folder 3:32)
- Burlington, Vermont, Champlain Shakespeare Festival, 1982. (Box-folder 3:33)
- Dorset, Vermont, Dorset Theater, 1979, 1981. (Box-folder 3:34)
- Charlottesville, Virginia, Ash Lawn Highland, 1993. (Box-folder 3:35)
- Jamestown, Virginia, Jamestown Festival, 1957. (Box-folder 3:36)
- Norfolk, Virginia, Virginia Opera Theater, 1982, 1984. (Box-folder 3:37)
- Vienna, Virginia, Wolf Trap, 1978-1980, 1985. (Box-folder 3:38)
- Vienna, Virginia, Wolf Trap. (Box-folder 3:39)
- Paris, France, Ballet Français de Nancy, 1989. (Box-folder 3:40)
- Paris, France, Comèdie Française 1985-1986, 1988, 1991. (Box-folder 3:41)
- Paris, France, Opèra Comique-Festival Gioacchino Rossini, 1992. (Box-folder 3:42)
- Paris, France, Opera de Paris, 1986, 1988. (Box-folder 3:43)
- Paris, France, Opera de Paris, 1988, 1991-1992. (Box-folder 3:44)
- Paris, France, Theatre Musical de Paris, 1992. (Box-folder 3:45)
- London, England, Adelphi Theatre, 1993. (Box-folder 3:46)
- London, England, Aldwych Theatre, 1993, 1995. (Box-folder 3:47)
- London, England, Royal National Theatre, 1994-1995. (Box-folder 3:48)
- London, England, Theatre Royal-Drury Lane, 1989. (Box-folder 3:49)
- Stratford-upon-Avon, England, Royal Shakespeare Company, 1994, 1996. (Box-folder 3:50)
- (No location available), Cinematech. (Box-folder 3:51)
- (No location available), Mon Uncle. (Box-folder 3:52)
- (No location available), National Symphony Orchestra. (Box-folder 3:53)
- (No location available), Vienna Volksoper-American Tour, 1984. (Box-folder 3:54)
- (No location available), Ringling Brothers and Barnum and Bailey Circus, 1978. (Box-folder 3:55)